# SUJEET KUMAR

226-975-2285 • kumar31@uwindsor.ca • https://www.linkedin.com/in/sujeet-kumar18/ • https://www.sujeetkumar.ca

## **PROFILE**

I am a hands-on operator and field leader with 3+ years of experience managing high-performing teams at Walmart and in plant environments. I sought to use my skillset to simplify and optimise processes, improve operational performance, implement change, and manage day-to-day operations with ownership and reliability. In my past and current role, I have been trusted to lead the implementation of strategic initiatives due to my sound judgement, ability to deal with ambiguity, and influence change in the teams I collaborate with.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Walmart Canada**

Lead Analyst, Compliance (store-fulfilled)

Jul 2023 - Present

- Collaborate with stakeholders to continuously improve compliance programs, build trust, and ensure regulatory adherence.
- Deliver comprehensive compliance and safety training to associates and managers at all levels.
- Conduct assessments in various compliance areas such as Health & Safety, Environmental, Anti Money Laundering, etc.
- Analyze data using Tableau to identify program gaps, determine root causes, and implement action plans for improved compliance.
- Participate in regulatory visits and resolve issues or fines through effective engagement.
- Manage accident file process, including investigations and resolution, ensuring adherence to safety protocols.

## **Walmart Canada**

Manager | E-Comm Operations (store-fulfilled)

Feb 2022 – Jul 2023

- Managed store-fulfilled E-Comm sales with a team of 25 associates, achieving a 25% YoY sales increase (~\$3.5M GMV) by
  optimizing inventory and reducing nil-pick rate from 45% to 15%.
- Acted as liaison between Store Support Centre, store associates, and customers, improving CSAT scores across Mississauga market.
- Selected by Corporate as main on-field POC for strategic home delivery pilot program, increasing orders from 0 to 120 WTD.
- Implemented <2H delivery (Express), maintaining 95% on-time delivery rate.
- Designed new SOP for order substitutes, boosting store NPS by 5 pts in 3 months.
- Optimized backroom operations, reducing pickup wait time from 15 to 5 mins using Tableau data analyzation.

### Lucky Industries, Pakistan

Continuous Improvement Engineer

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

- Conducted time & motion studies, implementing LSS principles for process improvements, yielding a 35% increase in gear production line output.
- Redefined process control limits, reducing parts defects by 20% in 6 months, lowering OpEx and improving customer retention.
- Led cross-functional teams to implement dock-yard management system, reducing trailer queues and shunting requirements.
- Developed and delivered Lean Manufacturing training programs, achieving a 25% reduction in process waste.
- Implemented Health & Safety standards, achieving a streak of zero shop incidents and minimizing plant downtime.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Windsor Master of Mechanical Engineering Jan 2020 – Apr 2021

Technical Skills: MATLAB, Minitab, PowerBI (user), Tableau (user), Excel, PowerPoint, SolidWorks, AutoCAD

Certifications: Certified Lean Six Sigma Green Belt, Process Improvement, Project Management

Training: Lean Six Sigma Green Belt, Power BI, Tableau, SQL & Data Visualization, HTML, CSS, JS

Reference: Taha Mirza, Senior Manager – Walmart Last Mile Delivery

Pawiterjit Rattan, Store Manager – Walmart | Ph: (416) 697-1752